watchdog.org 2015-09-05

# Privacy Policy - Watchdog.org

**Watchdog.org Privacy policy**

**Updated: September 28,   2012**

Thank you for visiting [Watchdog.org](http://watchdog.org/ "Watchdog.org")!  This website is a project of the [Franklin Center for Government and Public Integrity](http://franklincenterhq.org/ "Franklin Center").  At the [Franklin Center](http://franklincenterhq.org/ "Franklin Center"), we are always doing our best to provide privacy and security of information that you share with us online at our website and via any e-communications and social networks.  We urge you to also take steps to protect the privacy of your personal information, such as safeguarding your passwords and logging off of the website after submitting personal information.  This privacy policy is designed to help you keep you and your information safe while you are visiting our websites while also providing you with information about security measures, precautions and legal requirements to secure your information.

**We Protect your Information**

Our website has a number of security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of the information under our control.  Our websites and technology have restricted access limited only to authorized staff and vendors.  This access applies to all electronic and physical security measures. Highly sensitive data including credit card information is additionally secured through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. Our servers are located in a locked, secure environment and are monitored on a continuing basis. ****

**How we gather information from users.**

How we collect and store information depends on the page you are visiting, the activities in which you elect to participate and the services provided. You can visit many pages on our site without providing any information. Other pages may prompt you to provide information, such as when you register for access to portions of our site, sign up for membership, request certain features (e.g., e-newsletters, news updates and other products.

**How do we use the information you provide?**

At the _**Franklin Center for Government & Public Integrity**_ and all associated web sites & projects, we may ask for your name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address.

We will use your e-mail address to provide you news and information about the Franklin Center for Government & Public Integrity Communications include a periodic e-Newsletter, event invitations & updates, urgent news of interest, or for fundraising support.

When you register, sign-up online or contribute, we may share your contact information with like-minded organizations that may be of interest to you.

**Contributing money online**

The _ **Franklin Center for Government & Public Integrity**_ is a non-profit organization and registered as a 501 (c)3 with the Internal Revenue Service (IRS).  Contributions to the Franklin Center for Government & Public Integrity are tax-deductible.  The _Franklin Center_ recommends that you keep all contribution receipts on hand for tax preparation and for your accountant or tax preparer.  The Franklin Center for Government & Public Integrity will not disclose the identity of its generous donors.

**We keep your IP Addresses safe**

We may or may not keep track of your IP address, which is the location of your computer or network on the Internet, for systems administration purposes. We also use page hits in the aggregate to track the popularity of pages that people visit in order to improve the quality of the site.  There is no personal identifiable information collected in our log files.

**Subscribing to Email Communications**

The **_Franklin Center for Government & Public Integrity_** will provide to its website users the option to subscribe to Email Communications, often referred to as e-communications, e-newsletters, e-updates or email solicitations.  The Franklin Center is not responsible for the subscription email address submitted by any user or subscriber to the Franklin Center’s database(s).  The Franklin Center, however, has the right to use discretion when communicating, by all means, to the email account provided by any user or subscriber.  The _Franklin Center for Government & Public Integrity _will do its best to protect users from spam subscriptions.  If you feel you have been improperly subscribed to the _Franklin Center’s_ Email Communications, please see “Unsubscribing from Email Communications” in this privacy policy.

**Unsubscribing from Email Communications**

If you wish to unsubscribe from our communications, please click on the link “Unsubscribe” at the bottom every mass email communication or you may request an unsubscribe by emailing info@watchdog.org.  We will process these requests to the best of our ability to comply with legal requirements, however, our contributor records will be continuously maintained in a separate secure database.

**Affiliated sites, linked sites and advertisements**

The **_Franklin Center for Government & Public Integrity_** expects its partners, potential advertisers and third-party affiliates to respect the privacy of its users. However, third parties, including our partners, advertisers, affiliates and other content providers accessible through our site, may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices.  
While on our site, our advertisers, promotional partners or other third parties may use cookies or other technology to attempt to identify some of your preferences or retrieve information about you.  
Please be careful and responsible whenever you are online. Should you choose to voluntarily disclose Personally Identifiable Information on our site, that information may be viewed publicly and can be collected and used by third parties without our knowledge and may result in unsolicited messages from other individuals or third parties. Such activities are beyond the control of the _Franklin Center for Government & Public Integrity_ and this policy.

This Website may be linked to other websites which are not under the control of and are not maintained by Franklin Center. Franklin Center is not responsible for the content of those sites. Franklin Center is providing these links to you only as a convenience, and the inclusion of any link to such sites does not imply endorsement by Franklin Center of those sites.

**Contacting us**

Our site links to a limited number of other websites such as media, blogs and other websites of interest to supporters of the _Franklin Center_.  The _Franklin Center_ is not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of these websites, however, we do our best to ensure that we are leading you to responsible and credible content.  For questions or for general contact, please contact:

[www.watchdog.org](http://watchdog.org/ "Watchdog.org")   c/o Watchdog.org Information Center Franklin Center for Government & Public Integrity 1229 King Street 3rd Floor Alexandria, VA 22314 Phone: (571) 384-2090 

info@watchdog.org

**Changes to this policy**

The **_Franklin Center for Government & Public Integrity_** reserves the right to change this privacy policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for changes. Your continued use of our site following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. Information collected prior to the time any change is posted will be used according to the rules and laws that applied at the time the information was collected.

**Governing law**

This policy and the use of this Site are governed by North Dakota law. Any claim related to the Site or this policy shall be brought in a federal or state court in the state of North Dakota, within one year after the claim arises. You agree no such claim may be brought as a class action.  Users of [franklincenterhq.org](http://franklincenterhq.org/ "Franklin Center") and any projects or affiliated websites of the _Franklin Center for Government and Public Integrity_ consent to the jurisdiction and venue of such court as the most convenient and appropriate for the resolution of disputes concerning this policy.  **Watchdog.org** & **franklincenterhq.org** are controlled, operated and administered entirely within the United States.  If you are located outside the United States, please note the information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. You hereby consent to this transfer.

In the event case of any conflict between the terms of this policy and the terms of any electronic or machine readable privacy policy, the terms of this written policy shall control.
